He came as a refugee from Iraq to Sweden as a 13-year-old.
Today he is 30 years old and a millionaire.
Mohammed Salih is a savings economist, stock market inspector and Instagram profile.
He is a podder, writer and dad-
-And today he is here to talk about his journey towards the million.
-Welcome here, Mohammed.
-Thanks.
So fun to have you here.
We will hear about your trip to the million today.
Or Kallinge that is the metropolis for me.
It's just there that I feel at home.
That you have this escape in the luggage, how has it affected your view of money and finances?
This is probably what has made me so interested and constantly want money.
It creates such security.
During the escape trip we did not even have money for food and clothes.
Then Mom got to beg clothes and food.
Although I will never end up in that situation in Sweden-
-So money is a damn security for me and the dependence on money comes from it.
What does it mean for you to be in Sweden?
It is difficult to explain with words.
My love for Sweden is really boundless.
There is nothing that I am so grateful for-
-As Sweden opened its arms to our family.
For after 13 years on escape-
-or 13 years of uncertainty before getting this residence permit-
-It can't describe how nice it felt.
Yes I did.
I knew this will not last for any length of time.
Hopefully I would become a millionaire before thirty.
Then I was 26 or something.
So four years left.
Then I felt I had to make some changes.
I earned about 28,000 gross.
Not very high salary, but not very low either.
But I knew I had to start working a little extra.
I waived SL cards and went back and forth to work-
-From Sundbyberg, it takes an hour and a half to go easy.
No outdoor lunches or outdoor dinners, I didn't go out at all.
For any length of time you can't live that way, but it was a short period of time-
-And I felt it was worth it.
Pretty big changes in my consumption ...
You tried to obtain revenue in other ways, you started a "flipping account".
It is the "stock test", a great role model both for me-
-and all ordinary people who only have a few hundred dollars to start saving with.
He started at SJ with a couple of hundred dollars and finally had SEK 140 million.
-What is so exciting about him?
-He shows that everyone can invest.
Everyone can create a great fortune through the stock exchange.
You did, but it has also looked like this.
A hardship you have had.
Yes, when I bought my very first stock.
The Marketing Group was delivered from the stock exchange-
-So it was a huge hardship.
But some patches on the tracks may come here.
A lesson: "Everyone makes mistakes."
Yes, that's it.
No matter how knowledgeable man is-
-How much you have plugged in, how well inserted you are in the industry-
-I is actually that everyone makes mistakes.
It is important not to make the same mistake.
An opportunity that meant a lot to you was this.
What do we see?
Did it also open a desire to be seen and heard more?
Yes, and above all to meet people and lecture.
It will be a completely different thing than just sitting digitally.
It was a big milestone.
What was your biggest motivation?
A huge driving force behind running the account and continuing with it-
-Ist know that people look up to me, do as I do, take hold of their financial
-Fears their parents to invest ...
It has been the biggest motivation and inspiration for me.
-Getting others to grab their finances.
-Can it not make you a little scared too?
-You get a great responsibility?
-Yes.
Therefore, you have to be careful what you do and communicate.
A little celebration with me and my partner.
"Shit, what a trip."
She has also helped me, had an understanding of four ore agencies in the hall ...
I felt I had to share the joy.
-We celebrated with champagne and food.
-Gud, what a wonderful.
Now we will have a look at which holdings have led Mohammed up to the million.
Voilà!
What we see here is a selection of the portfolio that you had-
-During the journey towards the million.
We have selected some of your biggest holdings.
You had a very large portfolio.
But here we have then picked out the investment company Kinnevik, SBB-
-Evolution and a fund - MS Asia Opportunity.
What was your investment strategy?
"Buy very much and very wide."
That was my strategy.